About

Data Engineer with around 4 years of experience in Designing and Implementing ML Models, ETL pipelines, Data Mesh and Analytics. Possess PGD in Big Data Analytics from CDAC ACTS (HQ), Pune. Seeking to leverage my Mathematical knowledge, Analytics abilities, and ML models development competency in the role of Data Analytics.

Contact

6

(+91) 8239-3838-47



rsohlot@gmail.com



Bangalore, IN



linkedin.com/in/rsohlot

https://rsohlot.github.io

Professional experience

2020 - Present

Data Engineer-II, Infinx HealthCare, Bangalore

- IRIS: An Insights dashboard to help client analyzing their revenue. Build on generalized ETL platform to make easier onboard for newer client implementation.
- IROS: A Data processing product with the capability to scale, contains pkgs for data quality check, logging as an event that then tracked with the help of kibana.
 Output: A/R Inventory data to maximize revenue recovery by prioritize using treebased ML models.
 - Tools/services used: python, pyspark, airflow, aws EMR, aws Redshift, glue crawler, glue catalog, athena, Quicksight.
- My Responsibility: Design and Implement the product.
- Data Processing: Transforming (containing 80 col derivation) 70 Lakh record in 5 min. (EMR + pyspark)

2019 - 2020

Associate Data Scientist, KratinLLC, Nagpur

- Designed a Time Series Model give accuracy up to 97% used to create an AI smart SAP tool to maximize the workforce utilization considering all the preferences and requirements. Results in saving the 500 miles every week of the workforce traveling.
- Estimated the future demand to get the best assignment of workforce. Tools used prophet, optaplanner, Django, plotly, pandas, docker.
- Designed and implemented the warehouse for the BI and analytics. Saved daily
 1 hr. task of the team to fetch, validate and store the data. This was done with
 Hadoop, hive, spark, hue, Apache Atlus, Apache ranger.

EDUCATION

CDAC -PGD Big Data Analytics

Pune Maharashtra 2018 – 2019

B.Tech. ECE

Rajasthan Technical University Jaipur, RJ 2010 – 2014

SKILLS

Machine Learning
Reinforcement Learning, GAN
Python, Java, R
Big Data, Spark, Hive, Kafka
SQL (DBMS)
Mathematics (Statistics, Calculus)

Pytorch, TensorFlow

CERTIFICATION

- Market Analysis Course (Jan 2017 – March 2017)
- ML, Coursera (May 2016- June 2017)
- Spark Working (Dec 2019 – Dec 2019)
- GAN with Pytorch (May 2020 – June 2020)
- AI: Feature Engineering (July 2020 – July 2020)

2016 - 2018

Co-Founder, WHT, Bhiwadi, RJ

 Founded WHT. It was a Logistics Firm. Learnt the Logistics business flow of Northern India. Firm manages complete workflow of goods for the various Industries.

Personal Projects

Open-Source Contribution

Chaos-genius (github)

- Design and discussion in adding new KPIs related to data metrics.
- Adding new features to product.